Meghna Agarwal

meghnaagarwal2807@gmail.com +91-9997972566 www.linkedin.com/in/meghna-agarwal

Summary

Five years of Industry experience in design, development & maintenance of web-based applications and micro services. Well skilled in solution implementations and problem identification. A supportive and flexible team player with a proven entrepreneurial approach towards business goals and objectives. Acquainted with Agile Methodology (Scrum Practices) like Sprint Planning, Daily Scrum, Sprint Review and Sprint Retrospective meetings

Technical Proficiency:

• Web Technologies: .NET Core, Asp. Net MVC, Web API, React JS, React Native, Angular JS, Angular

• Databases: Microsoft SQL Server, PostgreSQL

• Cloud Technologies: Heroku, Azure

• IDE: Visual Studio, VS Code

• Source Control: GIT, TFS

• Testing Tools: Fiddler, Postman

Experience

Organization : GAVS

Duration : Dec 2021– Present **Designation** : Software Engineer

Organization : Softtrends Software Private Limited

Duration : Jan 2018– Nov 2021 **Designation** : Software Developer

Projects/Clients

MainPro+

Dec 2021 - Present

Working on the DCE and CAC projects in CFPC(The College Of Family Physicians Of Canada)

DCE: Direct credit entry. DCE activities are created by Providers and staff person by uploading the excel template and after that dce activities will be sent to holding area in mainpro+.

CAC: Certificates of Added Competence (CACs) provide a means of recognizing those family physicians who have achieved a defined level of competence and commitment to maintenance.

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Worked on the UI design of the application in Angular
- Develop & Enhance multiple Web API in .net
- Develop & Enhance Stored Procedures in SQL
- Analyzing business requirements and showing demo to client on release basis.
- Test the Web API by using Postman
- Use of TFS and GIT for check in and cloning the code.

DeDup

Sept 2020 - Nov 2021

Working on the **DeDup**, addon of Heroku, which is used to remove duplicates and merge data of database tables.

Roles and Responsibilities:

• Worked on the UI design of the add-on.

- Worked on the backend with postgres database and create multiple tables in the database.
- Develop multiple Web API
- Test it with single and multiple tables of database

OASYS

Dec 2018 - Aug 2020

Implement the Progressive Web App(PWA) for the existing website(Crossfire Inflow) for Inflow doctor and Patient portal.

Roles and Responsibility:

- Develop the PWA in React and Javascript as per the requirements provided by Client.
- Call the APIs in the project using AJAX.
- Analyzing business requirements and showing demo to client on release basis.
- Develop & Enhance Web API Services

One Direct Health Network

Oct 2018 - Nov 2019

Enhancing the features of **T-REX (Restoring Range of Motion in less time)** web application for a US Based One Direct Health Network Company.

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Develop the responsive site in .Net Core as per the requirements provided by Client.
- Analyzing business requirements and showing demo to client on release basis.
- Create the Highcharts in the projects for demonstrating the Range of Motion.
- Develop the application in a customizable way.
- Develop & Enhance Web API Services
- Deploy the code on cloud(Heroku) platform.
- Test the Web API using Fiddler.

Workers In Motion(WIM)

Feb 2018 - Sept 2018

Enhancing the features of **Workers In Motion Web Application** which is used to capture GPS location, photos, and signatures along with time-stamp. It helps to tracks and monitors everything and makes the employees more productive.

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Enhancement of the application using C# with MVC framework as per requirement.
- Participate in analyzing business requirements by connecting up with Client.
- Provide steps to improvise the Application on performance and User experience level.
- Enhance the functionality of report generation in pdf format in the code.
- Test the Web API using Fiddler.
- Deploy the code on cloud(Heroku) platform.

Education

Bachelor of Technology (Moradabad Institute of Technology)

Field: Computer Science

Grade: 77%

During: 2013 – 2017

Sacred Heart Convent School

Metric (XII) Grade: 80% Subjects: PCM with Java

High School (X) Grade: 85.2%

Personal Details

Date of Birth:July 28, 1995Marital Status:UnmarriedLanguages:English, Hindi

Nationality: India